the searches for insurance in india on
mobile have been on the rise
and with an increased interest in the
category customers expect to do
even insurance related transactions on
their smartphones
but how do you make purchasing and
renewing a rather complicated product
like insurance
easy our intensive research gave us a
starting point
we figured that people usually assume
that insurance is a complicated category
most people forgot to renew their
policies and even if they remembered
they didn't renew it because the process
was rather cumbersome
we decided to build a mobile application
that solved both these problems
our application ensure makes insurance
transactions
really really easy customers can buy and
renew policies with one click
and pay through their smartphones
without the need of an agent
claimed status can be checked through
the application itself
integrated with google maps this
application gives the customers
a list of cashless hospitals and garages
in the vicinity
customers are given a digital copy of
their policy
as well as a digital health card saving
them the effort of carrying a physical
paper print out
this application was met with instant
success
icici lombard launched two-wheeler
four-wheeler
and international travel insurance on
the mobile
in october 2013. in just a month
insurance codes taken on the mobile and
sales
both increased by three times